Based on the untold true story
Outlaw King is a action, history, war film directed by David Mackenzie.
Forced into exile by the English after being crowned King of Scotland,
legendary warrior Robert the Bruce fights to reclaim the throne.
Robert Bruce, Earl of Carrick, played by Chris Pine.
James Douglas, Lord of Douglas, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson.
Elizabeth Burgh, played by Florence Pugh.
Edward, Prince of Wales, played by Billy Howle.
Aymer de Valence, Earl of Pembroke, played by Sam Spruell.
Angus Og Macdonald, Lord of Islay, played by Tony Curran.
Outlaw King is a 2018 historical action drama film,
co-written, produced, and directed by David Mackenzie.
Chris Pine stars as Scottish king Robert the Bruce during
the Scottish Wars of Independence in 1304–07.
The ensemble cast also features Aaron Taylor-Johnson, Florence Pugh, Billy Howle, Sam
Spruell, Tony Curran, Callan Mulvey, James Cosmo and Stephen Dillane.
Outlaw King premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 6,
2018, and was released on streaming on November 9 by Netflix.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised its production design, sets,
performances, and choreography, but criticised its historical inaccuracies and clichés.
The film explores themes of scotland, castle,
exile, biography, based on true story.